# MICHAEL KONIG

7101 Goodwin Road, Everson, WA 98247 · 707-235-2511

michael.konig@konigconcepts.com · www.linkedin.com/in/michaelkonigmk · konigconcepts.com

I am an automotive professional with a focus on project management, innovative engineering solutions, and evaluating ways to bring the next generation of driving experience to the industry. As the world moves to being more technology reliant, I would like to work with a strong team to bridge the gap between traditional automotive passion and new technical knowledge. I have a willingness to relocate to keep me to the right opportunities.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**JANUARY 2016 - JUNE 2018** 

### PROJECT MANAGER, WWU RACING, FORMULA SAE TEAM

Managed a team of 45 students to build a Formula SAE race car in one year. Built a start-up style business model that replicates industry. Established goals for the year and guided the team along a path to reach those goals. Raised, managed, spent, and reconciled a \$25,000 budget. Developed each team member into creative, detail oriented, thoughtful, and prepared engineers that functioned as a cohesive team.

**JANUARY 2006 – OCTOBER 2011** 

#### **DRIVING INSTRUCTOR/GUEST RELATIONS, WORLD CLASS DRVING**

Responsible for maximizing high-end clients' experiences. Instructed clients on driving a fleet of exotic cars. Marketed events and tours; handled cross country travel/catering logistics. Maintained exotic fleet.

**FEBRUARY 2003 – AUGUST 2013** 

## FRONT OF THE HOUSE MANAGER, IL POSTO TRATTORIA / FUME BISTRO & BAR

Hired, trained, and managed 10 to 15 employees in two full service, up-scale restaurants. Assisted in developing menus, staff, interior design, policies, and marketing. Handled finances and HR on a daily basis.

# **EDUCATION**

**GRADUATION DATE: JUNE 2018 (EXPECTED)** 

# INDUSTRIAL TECHNOLOGY-VEHICLE DESIGN, BS, WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY

Lab based major with critical aspects of mechanical engineering, vehicle design, hands on manufacturing, composites, CAD modeling, vehicle dynamics, and project management. Recipient of the Don Moon Scholarship, the Schaad Scholarship, and the Western Grant. **Expected graduating GPA: 3.33** 

**COMPLETION DATE: MAY 2005** 

# **MECHANIC/DRIVING TRAINING PROGRAM, JIM RUSSELL RACING SCHOOL**

Hands on racing mechanic training program. Learned ground up builds of open wheel race cars, vehicle dynamics, repairs, composite training, maintenance of a fleet of high performance cars for Audi, and motorsports business management. Attended composites classes at Abaris Training. Year-long driving school in parallel to the mechanic program with some of the top instructors in the world. Heavily involved in the building/prepping of the fleet of Formula 3 cars currently used at Simraceway Driving School.

#### **SKILLS**

- Large scale project management
- Time management/task prioritization
- Commitment and a strong desire to get the job done
- Proficient with current technology trends and processes
- Motivating teams to work together towards a common goal
- Building plans, timelines, keep documentation
- Steady and focused in high pressure situations
- Ability to work dynamically

<sup>\*</sup>Portfolio and a more detailed resume available on website or LinkedIn listed above